（真方ジン）
レイツェル。　ここで　一体　何が…？
Raetsel, what's gonna happen here?
（レイツェル）
終わるのよ　ジンと私の旅が。
Our journey is gonna end here.
旅が…　終わる？
Our journey is gonna end?
そうよ。　ここで。
Yeah. Right here.
カイト君!?
Kaito!
Daimon Kaito!
大門…　カイト！
There's no escape 'cause I'm now believing my fate
カイト君…　どうして　ここに？
Kaito, why are you here?
（大門カイト）元気だったか？　ジン。
You're all right, Jin?
ああ　もちろん。
Yeah, of course...
やっぱり来たわね　大門カイト。
I knew you'd come, Daimon Kaito.
ＰＯＧの捜査網も大したものだわ。
The POG's intelligence networks sure are amazing.
（キュービック・Ｇ）それは違うよ。→
I think you're misunderstanding something.
We were told about this place by Enigma!
僕らに　この場所を教えたのは
エニグマさ。
（逆之上ギャモン）
てめえは　あいつに利用されて→
You're like a cat dancing for catnip in the palm of his hand!
マタタビ嗅いだ猫みてえに
踊らされてんだよ。
レイツェル　２人で話がしたい。
（井藤ノノハ）カイト…。
Raetsel, I want to talk with you privately.
Kaito?
いいわ。
私も　君に話したい事があるから。
Very well. There's something I need to discuss with you as well.
だったら　私も　立ち会う。
えっ　ノノハ!?
Then I'll go too!
Nonoha!
You're so stupid you can't say what you mean properly!
カイト　バカだから
言いたい事　ちゃんと言えないし。
Don't bring up my stupidity now!
おめえなぁ！
ここで　バカを持ち出すなよ！
But you admit you are stupid!
バカって事は認めるのね？
うっ…　ちょっとしか認めねえ。
Just a little.
いいわ。
（カイト　ノノハ）えっ？
I don't mind.
（レイツェル）あなた　大門カイトにとって
特別な人みたいだから→
You seem to be quite special to Daimon Kaito.
I'll let you stay by his side as long as possible.
少しでも長く　いさせてあげる。
Decoding the Pythagoras Document is tougher than I expected.
（フリーセル）さすがに難解だね
ピタゴラス文書の解読。
（ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド）
ああ。　だが　僕たちなら　できる。
Yeah, but I'm sure we can do it.
秘密の帳に包まれた
神のパズルの存在理由を→
The Puzzle of God might be shrouded in mystery,
必ず　解き明かしてみせる！
but I'm gonna find out why it exists!
うん。　カイトのために！
For Kaito.
（レイツェル）全部うそ？
ああ。
It's all lies?!
Yeah.
ジンが　パズルを憎んでたってのも→
Those stories about how Jin hated puzzles
パズラーのせん滅を望んでたってのも
全部　エニグマの作り話だ。
and wanted to annihilate all puzzlers
were all made up by Enigma.
だまされてたのよ　あなたも
ジンさんも　マスターブレインも。
You were tricked as well.
Jin and the Master Brains too.
エニグマの個人的な復讐のために
利用されていたの。
Enigma just used you for his personal revenge!
Not to mention how insane his reason for wanting revenge is.
その復讐だって
逆恨みもいいとこだ。
恋人が死んだのは
パズルのせいじゃねえ。
It wasn't the puzzle's fault that his lover died.
We're telling the truth.
全部　本当の事よ。
信じて　レイツェル　お願い！
Believe us! Please, Raetsel!
フッ　気付いていたわ。
え？
I realized it too.
That I was being used,
利用されてる事。
and that Jin is actually probably the way you believe he is.
そして　君の信じるジンが
多分　本当のジンだって事も。
つじつまが合うのよ　その方が。
Things just make more sense that way.
And I could love a Jin like that more.
それに　そんなジンの方が
私も好き。
レイツェル…。
よかった。
Raetsel...
I'm so glad to hear that!
そうよ　最初から間違ってたのよ。
The whole premise was wrong!
Jin's very important to both of you! It makes no sense for you to fight!
ジンさんを好きな２人が
いがみ合うなんて　おかしいもん。
Kaito can convince her, right?
（キュービック）カイト　説得できるよね。
もしもし。→
Hello?
はい…　はい。　分かりました。→
Yeah.
Of course.
Got it.
イワシミズ君！　軸川先輩が
状況を日本に送ってほしいって！
Iwashimizu! Jikukawa wants a status report sent over!
（イワシミズ君）了解　了解　了解…。
Roger.
But nothing's gonna happen.
けど…　何も起きないよ。→
Recording.
They've got no reason to fight now.
これ以上　２人が戦う意味は
ないんだから。
（ギャモン）だといいがな…。
I hope you're right.
I think I know this puzzle...
心の声
（ジン）このパズル…　どこかで…。
（レイツェル）ジンは誰にも渡さない。
I'm not letting anyone take Jin.
I didn't go on a journey with Jin to return his memories.
私が　ジンと旅に出たのは
記憶を取り戻させるためじゃない。
取り戻させないため。
It was so you couldn't make them return.
記憶が戻ったら　ジンは
私ではなく君を選ぶから。
If he got his memories back, he'd pick you over me.
レイツェル！　何言ってんだ　お前。
What the hell are you talking about?
君に話したい事だけど…→
I wanted to tell you that I think Jin's gonna regain his memories soon.
多分　もう少しで
ジンは記憶を取り戻すと思う。
何だって!?
What?
悪くない…。
Not bad.
心の声
（ジン）さすがは
ファイ・ブレイン　真方ジンの造りし　パズル。
The Phi Brain Makata Jin made it after all.
ジンの様子が変なの。
時々　ほんの一瞬だけど→
Jin's acting weird.
Every now and then, just for a moment, he turns into a Jin neither of us knows.
君も私も知らないジンになる。
何だよ　それ。
What do you mean?
怖いの。　もし　あれが
本当のジンだとしたら…。
I'm scared. What if that's the real Jin?
でも　私は　それでも…。
But not even that can make me falter.
レイツェル。
Raetsel...
恐らく　今　強いきっかけを
与えれば　ジンは記憶を取り戻す。
I'd say that at this point, given the right trigger, Jin's memories will return.
それが　キリング・コロシアム。　あのパズルよ。
I think the trigger is the Killing Colosseum,
that puzzle out there.
It's the final puzzle Jin and I made together.
（レイツェル）ジンと私が２人で設計した
最後の一つ。→
「いつか造ってみたい」って
そう言ってたわ。→
He said he wanted to try making one sometime.
だから　私が造ってあげた→
I made that puzzle, full of my love for him.
ジンの思いの詰まった
あのパズルで→
If you and I fight to the death in it, I'm sure...
君と私が　命を懸けて戦えば…。
命を懸けて？
To the death?
Daimon Kaito, this is your best chance to help Jin regain his memories.
大門カイト。　これは　ジンの記憶を
取り戻す　最大のチャンス。
If you win, Jin will be yours alone.
君が勝てば　ジンは君だけのもの。
でも　たとえ　ジンが君を選んでも
君がいなければ…。
On the other hand, even if he were to pick you, if you're no more...
Kaito won't do that!
カイトが　やるわけないでしょ！
Kaito wouldn't take Jin from you!
カイトは　あなたから
ジンさんを奪ったりしない。
Why would you say that?
何で　そんな事　言うの!?
彼には　あなたや仲間がいる。
He has you and other friends too.
でも　私には　ジンだけ。
えっ？
I only have Jin.
ジンが　私の全て。
He's my everything.
He weighs differently in our lives!
重さが違うのよ…　ジンの！
Jinjin!
Jinjin...
I see...
そうだったんだ…。
え？
I made this puzzle...
（ジン）このパズルを造ったのは　僕。
What's that?
これは？
キリング・コロシアムの構想図。
The layout of the Killing Colosseum.
It wouldn't be fair if only I knew it.
私だけ知ってるんじゃ
フェアじゃないから。
カイト？
Kaito...
アハハ…　私　な～んか　すご～く
嫌な予感がするんですけど。
I've got a really bad feeling about this.
もう十分だ。
フッ。
This is enough.
俺に解けないパズルは　ねえ。
え？
There's no puzzle I can't solve.
カイト。
Kaito,
あんた　やっぱ　大バカ～！
you're such a complete idiot!
We couldn't stop them...
（キュービック）止められなかったね。
ああ。　聞く耳　持たずだったな
２人とも。
Yeah, deaf ears and so on.
カイト…。
Kaito...
There's no going back now. Are you ready?
もう　後戻りは　できないわ。→
覚悟はいい？
ああ。
Yeah.
パズルタイムの…　始まりよ！
It's puzzle time!
カイト君！　レイツェル！
チッ　始まっちまった。
Kaito! Raetsel!
Dang! It started.
（軸川ソウジ）学園長　これは…。
Principal... This...
（解道バロン）ええ。　恐るべきパズルです。
Yeah. It's a fearsome puzzle.
While dodging the giant boulders,
（バロン）転がる巨大な鉄球を
かわしつつ→
５層のコロシアムの最下層から
最上層の出口を目指す　対戦パズル。
they must get from the bottom of the 5-level Colosseum to an exit on the top level.
A duel puzzle.
コロシアムには　分岐点が点在。
There are forking points too.
鉄球は　標示板の指示に従い→
The boulders follow the signs and fall to the left or right, or continue straight.
落下して
右へ　左へ　そのまま通過の→
３とおりの動きをとり→
Every time a boulder passes one, the sign changes.
鉄球が通る度　自動的に
別の標示に切り替わる。
分岐点は　カイト君が操作できるもの
レイツェルが操作できるもの→
There are fork points Kaito can control, and fork points Raetsel can control.
There are also some that neither of them can control.
２人とも操作できないものの
３種類。
（バロン）そして　敗北者は
出口を閉じられ→
Once one of them gets out, the exit will be closed,
命尽きるまで
鉄球に追われ続ける。
locking the other one in for a short life of running from the boulders.
Why would you build such a puzzle?
こんなパズルを生み出してまで
お前は…。
I won't let him take Jin!
心の声
（レイツェル）ジンは絶対に渡さない。
I love Jin more than everyone else!
心の声
（レイツェル）誰よりも
ジンを愛してるのは…　私！
Kaito, watch out!
カイト　危ない！
くそっ！
Dammit!
（ジン）
む…　むごい。　むごすぎる…。
It's cruel... So very cruel...
人間をおとしめ　弄び…
まるで　神のパズル。
It looks down on and toys around with people...
It's like a puzzle of god.
A puzzle of god?
神のパズルだと？
うっ！
（イワシミズ君）脳波異常　脳波異常。
Abnormal brainwaves.
Are you all right, Jin?
大丈夫？　ジンさん。
（イワシミズ君）危険　危険　危険…。
Danger.
駄目だ　記憶を取り戻しては…。
（イワシミズ君）異常検知　危険　危険！
I mustn't regain my memories!
Irregularity detected.
Danger!
ギャモン。
ああ。
Gammon!
I think Raetsel might've been right
このバトルが終わった時
ジンは記憶を取り戻す。
about his memories returning once this battle is over.
レイツェルの言うとおりかもしれねえ。
でも　そのためには　カイトかレイツェルの
どちらかが犠牲に…。
But for that, Kaito or Raetsel must become a sacrifice...
思うに　カイトには見えてる。
え？
I think... Kaito saw it.
心の声
俺は見た…　未来を。→
I saw it.
The future.
I believe in that future!
あの未来を　俺は信じる！→
エニグマの復讐のパズルから
ジンとレイツェルを解放する！
I'm gonna free Jin and Raetsel from Enigma's puzzle of vengeance!
Just a little more, Rook.
あと少しだね　ルーク。
ああ。　でも…。
Yeah, but...
So you can feel it too?
やっぱり　君も感じるのかい？
何なんだろう？
この不吉な予感は…。
What could this ominous premonition be?
解読結果を知るのが
ひどく怖いよ…。
I'm honestly scared of actually breaking this code.
あっ！　カイト…。
Kaito!
What are you doing?
どういうつもり？
さあな。
Who knows?
これからが　本当の勝負よ！
The real battle starts now!
Right!
心の声
いいんだ…　これでいいんだ。
Good. This is good.
分かった！　カイトの考えが。→
I see what Kaito's doing!
見ろ　あれを！→
Look at it!
このまま行けば　２人は同時に
出口へ　たどりつく。→
This way they're gonna make it to the exit at the same time!
バトルは　引き分けだ！
It's gonna end in a draw!
（キュービック）ほんとだ！
（ギャモン）カイトの野郎→
You're right!
Damn that Kaito! He's been aiming for this all along!
最初から　これを
ねらってやがったのか！
Draw.
カイト君…。
Kaito...
ジン!?
ジン！
Jin!
エニグマ　てめえ！
Damn you, Enigma!
（エニグマ）真方ジン
貴様も　パズルに参加させてやる。
Makata Jin! I'll make you take part in the fun as well.
You can watch the two people who idolize you die in your puzzle,
貴様を慕う２人が
貴様のパズルで散るのを見届け→
貴様も　くたばれ！
then die yourself!
待ってろ　ジン！
ジン！
Wait, Jin!
Jin!
Kaito! Raetsel!
（ジン）カイト君　レイツェル
駄目だ…　来るな　戻るんだ。
No! Don't come here! Go back!
（レイツェル）鉄球が　次々　ジンに！
The balls are closing in on him!
Crap! There's no end to them!
くっそ～
これじゃあ　きりがねえ！
カイト　レイツェル。
（アナ）ジンジン…。
Kaito... Raetsel...
Jinjin...
No! I mustn't regain my memories!
いけない…　僕は記憶を…→
記憶を取り戻しては
いけないんだ。→
僕の造ったパズルで
カイト君と　レイツェルが…。
Kaito and Raetsel are in a puzzle I made, about to—
駄目だ！　そんな事…　駄目だ！
No! I can't let that happen!
見ているかい？　ラヴーシュカ。
Are you watching, Lovushka?
もうすぐ　真方ジンと
２人のファイ・ブレインの子供たちが→
Makata Jin and two children of the Phi Brain will be in hell soon.
地獄へ落ちる。→
これが　僕たちの復讐のパズル…。
This is our puzzle of vengeance.
うぅ…。　僕は　僕は　僕は…。
I... I... I...
うぐっ！
I'm not gonna accept that future!
そんな未来…　認めるかぁ～！
ジン…。
Jin?!
あっ！
ジン!?
Jin!
あ…　あぁ…。
ジン？
Jin?
カイト　レイツェル　あとは俺に任せろ。
Kaito, Raetsel.
Leave the rest to me.
（レイツェル　カイト）あ…。
２人とも　今日まで
つらい思いをさせて→
Sorry for causing you so much trouble up until now.
すまなかったな。
Jin...
ジン　記憶が戻ったのか？
You got your memories back?
話は後だ。
We'll talk later.
これは　俺のパズルだ。
俺なら脱出できる。　行くぞ！
This is my puzzle. I can get out.
Come with me!
学園長！
Principal!
ジンが帰ってきた…。
Jin's back...
鉄球が！
A boulder!
こっちだ。
This way!
そうだ！　カイト。
That's right, Kaito!
Good move, Raetsel!
それでいい！　レイツェル。
Thanks!
（エニグマ）
無駄だ。　逃げ場は　どこにもない。
Pointless.
There's no escape.
Just a little further!
もう少しだ。
Good. We're safe now.
（ジン）よし　もう大丈夫だ。
ジン　もしかして　ここは…。
そうだ。
What?
Is this spot...
Yeah. No boulders will ever pass here.
この場所だけは　鉄球が
絶対に通らない。
えっ？
対戦者が危機に陥った時
ここに逃げれば→
I engineered this as a safe spot for the loser of the battle.
助かるよう設計した。→
俺のパズルは過酷だが
人殺しのパズルじゃない。
My puzzles might be tough, but they're not murderous.
あ…。
だよな！　ジンのパズルだもんな！
I knew it! It's your puzzle!
そして　設計図どおりに
造られていれば…。
And if it's built according to the plans...
あっ！
これは…。
No way!
What?!
何!?
さあ　早く。
Hurry now!
心の声
（ジン）カイト　レイツェル…　お別れだ。
Kaito, Raetsel... Goodbye.
カイト！
（アナ　キュービック　イワシミズ君）カイト！
Kaito!
カイト。
やったな　カイト！
ああ。
Kaito!
You did it, Kaito!
レイレイ　よかったね。
Everything's all right now, right, Raerae?
Makata Jin!
（エニグマ）真方ジン！
エニグマ！
Enigma!
貴様…　許さん！　許さんぞ！
You'll pay! I'll make you pay!
黙れ。
Silence.
Who are you?
あなた…　誰？
（ルーク）これは…。
No way!
これが…　神のパズルの正体。
Is this the truth behind the Puzzle of God?
カイト！　ジンの記憶を
復活させては駄目だ！
Kaito! You mustn't let Jin's memories return!
真方ジンは消滅した。
Makata Jin is gone.
I am the one with the brain of a god,
私は　神の頭脳を持つ者…
ファイ・ブレインの　オルペウス。
the Phi Brain, Orpheus.
Orpheus?!
オルペウス…　だと？
Preview
Jin was overtaken by...
Did he call himself Orpheus?